艾  肯  影  业
帧存储视效工作室
Framestore CFC  (英国)
国  家  彩  票
奖  励  基  金
英  国 电 影        协 会
艾   肯   国   际   娱   乐
帧存储视效工作室
英    国    电    影    协    会
发     行
联   合   发   行
太     平     洋     电     影
电       视       委       员       会
丹  电  影  和  伊  甸  园  影  业
制      作
你刚刚只是做了个恶梦 只是个恶梦 宝贝
You're just having a bad dream. That's all, baby.
只是个恶梦
That's all it was.
恶梦让你觉得你看到了实际上不存在的东西
Bad dreams make you think you've seen things that you haven't.
知道我做了恶梦之后会怎么做么?
You know what I do when I have a bad dream?
我会闭上眼睛 想些美好的事情
I close my eyes and I think of something nice.
例如和你在一起
Like being here with you.
恐 怖 游 轮
恐  怖  游  轮
梅 丽 莎 · 乔 治
迈 克 尔 · 多 曼
瑞 秋 · 卡 帕 尼
亨 利 · 尼 克 松
快点 宝贝 我们要迟到了
Hurry up, sweetheart. We're gonna be late.
艾 玛 · 朗
利 亚 姆 · 海 姆 斯 沃 斯
凯 利 · 马 丁 · 瓦 格 纳
选 角 导 演
妮 基 · 巴 雷 特
摄  影  指  导
罗伯特·汉弗莱    美国电影摄影协会
艺  术  指  导
梅 林 达 · 德 林
可恶
Shit.
剪  辑
斯 图 尔 特 · 加 泽 德
作    曲
克 里 斯 蒂 安 · 亨 森
杰克?
Jack?
看到有人按我的门铃么?
Did you see someone ring my doorbell?
没有
No.
知道了 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
视  觉  特  效  总  监
伊 万 · 莫 兰
筹 划  制 片 人
汤 姆 · 霍 费
格雷格
“三角号”
港口
八点三十分
执  行  制  片  人
史 蒂 夫 · 诺 里 斯
史 黛 芬 尼 · 休 伊
马 克 · 古 德
我都清理干净了 宝贝
I cleaned everything away, sweetheart.
一切都跟以前一模一样
Everything is exactly the way it was before.
干净又漂亮 看 看 看到了么?
They're clean and shiny. Look. Look. You see?
好了 好了 只要闭上眼睛
Okay, all right. Just close your eyes.
制  作  人
克 里 斯 · 布 朗
贾 森 · 纽 马 克
朱 莉 · 贝 恩 斯
“阳光之州”佛罗里达州
再见
欢 迎
再 来
编  剧  和  导  演
克 里 斯 托 弗 · 史 密 斯
三 角 号
喔 你好啊 水手
Well, hello, sailor.
嗨!
Hi!
能上来吗?
Permission to come aboard?
宝贝 拿着这个
Honey, hold this.
抱歉昨天没能来 因为某人又工作到太晚
So sorry we couldn't make it yesterday. Somebody was working late again.
最近怎样 莎?
How're you doing, Sal?
很好 你呢?
I'm good. How are you?
我也很好
I'm all right.
看看你呀
Look at you.
喜欢吗?
Do you like it?
看起来棒极了
You look great.
真的么? 我差点把它扔掉呢
Really? I just kinda threw it on.
她打扮了足有一个星期
She's had outfits laid out for a week.
你真会胡扯 你知道我老公这人
You're such a liar. You know my husband.
我不会听他说的 你知道的
I don't listen to what he says. You know that.
我带了我的蜜友过来 希德 她可是个大好人
I brought my really good friend, Heather. She's so nice.
答应我对她多用点心
Promise me you'll be attentive.
最近怎样 老兄?
How're you doing, man?
她不该带人来的
She's not to bring anyone.
你不喜欢她? 相信我 她是莎莉的朋友里面最漂亮的
You don't like her? Believe me, she's the best looking of Sally's friends.
而且也不唠叨
Which it doesn't say much.
可我让你别带人的
I asked you not to.
跟一个18岁男孩住同一条船却不让带女人...
You're living on a boat with an 18-year old boy and you're saying no girls.
格雷 这是希德
Greg, this is Heather.
她是我很好的朋友 我觉得你们应该见个面
She's a very good friend of mine, and I just thought you guys should meet.
嗨!
Hi.
抱歉 容我离开一下
Can you just excuse me for a moment?
洁西 你还好吗?
Jess. You okay?
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
嘿 出什么事了?
Hey. What happened?
嘿 到底出什么事了?
Hey. What's the matter?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你道什么歉啊
You've got nothing to apologize for.
怎么了? 你还好吗?
What is it? Are you okay?
我只是有点累
I'm just tired.
喔 听着 如果你不想的话 我们不一定非得今天出航
Well, listen, we don't have to go today if you don't want to.
不 我们走 我-我想
No, we do. I-I wanna go.
真的吗?
You sure?
是的
Yeah.
是的? 好 来吧 上来这儿
Yeah? Okay, come on. Come up here.
这是莎莉和她丈夫 唐尼
This is Sally and her husband, Downey.
这是希德 莎莉的朋友 你应该还记得维多
This is Heather, Sally's friend. You remember Victor.
现在让我们起航吧!
So let's go sailing!
好
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
你怎么样?
You okay?
格雷还好吗?
Is Greg okay?
好啊 他在上面
He's fine. He's upstairs.
你睡了几个小时了
You've been asleep for a couple of hours.
我做了个恶梦
I had this terrible dream.
什么内容?
What about?
不记得了
I don't remember.
要是我就不烦那个
I wouldn't worry.
因为恶梦能够释放现实中的压力
Apparently bad dreams cure you of real life stress.
这可是真正的香槟 要些吗?
As indeed does champagne. You want some?
是的
Yeah.
唐尼 能不能帮个忙?
Downey, wanna give me a hand, please?
维多 我可是船长的客人 不过 好吧 我会帮你的
Actually, Victor, I'm a guest of the Captain's, but yes, I witt help you.
维多 在码头的时候是怎么回事?
Victor, what was that back there at the harbor?
什么?
What?
我问洁西是否还好的时候你说不
I asked Jess if she was all right and you said no.
你不是告诉我她会带小孩一起来的吗?
You told me she was bringing the little boy along.
可是跟她在一起的时候 我问她孩子在哪儿?
When I was walking with her in the harbor I asked where he was.
她却记不得了
She couldn't remember.
她愣了差不多20秒
She stared into space for like 20 seconds
然后说在学校
and then she said he's at school.
所以...?
So?
呃 今天是星期六 学校放假
Well, it's Saturday. Ain't no school today.
也许她儿子是上一所每天都上课的特殊学校
Her son goes to a special needs school and it's open every day.
对她好点
Be nice to her.
- 没问题 - 那就好
- All right. - All right.
你们一起晒日光浴吗?
Do you boys sunbathe together?
有时
Sometimes.
香槟算不上极品但够冰 要些吗?
The champagne is not great but it is cold. Want some?
不了 谢谢
No thanks.
好吧 那我自己多喝点
Okay, more for me.
嘿 感觉怎么样?
Hey, how are you feeling?
真抱歉 我真不知道怎么会累成这样
I'm sorry, I didn't realize how tired I was.
你又道歉 再这样的话我就把你扔出去
You apologize one more time, and I'm gonna throw you overboard.
来这儿
Here.
现在好些了吧?
You all right?
是的
Yeah.
它以为我们是渔船
He thinks we're a fishing hoat.
它饿了
He's gonna go hungry.
想掌舵么?
You want to steer?
不
Nah.
试试吧
Go on.
我应该往那个方向?
Which way do I aim?
往那个方向
You're gonna aim that way.
很简单 对不对?
It's easy, right?
就是说 有时候她会做服务生
So, she's a waitress at some diner.
他们很谈得来 要变成朋友了
At least there they talk. They became friends.
哦 她还有个孤僻的儿子
Oh, and she has an autistic son.
所以他们只不过是朋友
So they're just friends.
莎莉!
Sally!
怎么 我应该说什么? 她有那么个儿子我很难过?
What do you want me to say? I'm sorry she has a retarded son?
是啊!
Yeah!
喔 很难过 你知道 但那是她的问题 不是格雷的
Well, I'm sorry. You know, that's not Greg's problem, that's hers.
你为什么看不惯她 因为她的短裤?
What is it, is it the shorts?
不! 希德 格雷是我的老朋友了
No! Heather, Greg's been my friend for a really long time.
我不能坐视不管 眼睁睁看他背上麻烦
I can't just sit back and watch him get shaken down.
她又没有这样
She isn't doing that.
好吧 希望不会 因为格雷太容易相信人了
Well, I hope not because Greg is far too trusting.
我有点喜欢那小伙子了
I'm kinda linking the boy.
啊 不 你不要 你就不能上去跟格雷谈一谈?
Uh, no, you're not. Can you please go up there and talk to Greg?
我觉得你们两个真的很匹配
I really think the two of you will be perfect for each other.
而且我也实在看不惯他跟她在一起
And I really don't like seeing him with her.
洁西 好了吗?
Jess, are you ready?
好了 升上去吧
Yeah, let her go.
好的
Yeah.
哇哦!
Woo!
嗯 你是怎么认识这些人的?
So, how do you know everyone?
维多 他一直跟我在一起
Victor, he's staying with me for good.
他在家里有些麻烦不得不跑出来
He got in troubte at home. He had to get away.
我发现他的时候他正睡在码头的储藏室后面
I found him sleeping behind the store at the harbor.
我们很谈得来 现在他住在这儿
You know, we got talking, and now he lives here.
就因为那样你就让他搬进来?
Just like that you let him move in?
嗯 我有三个房间 反正用不了
Well, I got three rooms. I can't sleep in them all.
唐尼 孩子的时候我就认识他了
And Downey, I've known him since I was a kid.
莎莉 他老婆 高中时认识的
Sally, his wife, I know her from high school.
八年级的时候我跟她约会过大约四天
I dated her for like four days in the eighth grade,
所以她可以算是我的"前女友"
so technically she's my ex.
他们看起来人都挺好的
They seem really nice.
是的 除了每年他们都觉得有必要
Yeah. Except for the fact that every year they feel obliged
给我介绍个女朋友
to bring me an eligible girl.
或许他们觉得你太孤单了
Maybe they think you're lonely.
你觉得我看上去孤单吗?
Do I give off lonely to you?
有时
Sometimes.
在餐厅看到你的时候 我可不觉得孤单 只觉得饿
When I come to see you at the diner, I'm not lonely, I'm hungry.
不过昨天明显的不同
Obviously yesterday was different.
昨天怎么了?
What happened yesterday?
昨天我不饿
Yesterday I was not hungry.
昨天我去餐厅只有一个目的就是邀请你出来航海
I came in with the sole purpose of inviting you sailing.
是吗?
You did?
是的
I did.
左转舵 风力不够
Turn at port side. We're losing wind.
让我稍微来调整一下
Let me check it for]ust a sec.
嗯 汤米怎样?
So, things are okay with Tommy?
老样子
The same.
每天都是老样子
Every day is the same.
汤米喜欢固定的模式 是的
Tommy likes the things to be a certain way. Yeah.
要是我做的稍有不同 就会失掉他的欢心
If I do one thing differently, I lose him.
怎么了? 以前从没见你这样过
What's the matter? I've never seen you like this before.
我不知道 我只是 呃 只是不跟汤米待在一起觉得很不安
I don't know. I just, uh, I just feel guilty when I'm not with Tommy.
那说明你是个好妈妈
That's because you're a good mother.
但你不可能时时刻刻都跟他在一起
But you can't be everywhere all of the times.
嘿 两位 噢!
Hey, guys. Oh!
谈得怎样?
How is it going?
挺好的
We're good.
我想问问是不是可以把洁西从你身边"偷走"一会儿
I was]ust wondering if I could steal Jess away from you.
莎莉非常想跟她谈一谈
Salty's dying to tatk to her.
我们正说在兴头上呢
We're kind of in the middle of something right now.
没关系 没关系 我-我应该去一下
No, no, it's okay. I-I should circulate.
嘿 说真的
Hey, just for the record,
我无意打扰的
I'm not interested.
唷 怎么回事?
Yo, what the fuck?
我们这儿风减弱了
Wind's dropped down on us.
风团不是减弱了 是飘走了
It's not dropped, it's gone.
太让人吃惊了
This is crazy.
你以前碰上过这个吗?
You ever seen this before?
是的 是的 只是没这么快
Yeah, yeah. Just not quite so sudden.
我们还能回得去吗? 没有风了
Are we okay to get home? There is no wind.
当然 当然 我们可以靠引擎 那不是问题
Yeah, yeah. We got an engine. It's not a problem.
只是 有点怪
It's just, it's weird.
格雷?
Greg?
那正常吗?
Is that normal?
喔 我可搞糊涂了 这是他妈的怎么回事
Okay, I'm fucking freaked, what the fuck.
三角号呼叫海岸警卫队 完毕
Triangle to coast guard. Over.
这里是海岸警卫队 请讲 完毕
Coast guard, go ahead. Over.
我们的帆船速度突然从7节降到0 你那里有什么异常吗? 完毕?
We've just gone from seven knots to absolute zero. You've got anything unusual? Over?
没什么异常 完毕
Nothing showing up. Over.
这里天色暗下来的很快 像是有暴风雨 完毕
It's darkening up pretty quick out here. Looks like an electrical storm. Over.
帮帮我 请帮帮我 能听到我吗?
Help me. Please. Can you hear me?
帮帮我 请帮帮我
Help me. Please, help me.
...杀了所有人 他们都死了 都死了
Killing everyone. They're dead. They're all dead.
我们听的到你 你在什么位置? 完毕
We hear you. What's your position? Over.
求救者 我们听到你了 你在什么位置? 完毕
Distressed caller, we hear you. What are your coordinates? Over.
海岸警卫队 是否听到求救电话? 我们跟她失去联系了 完毕
Coast guard, did you hear a distress call? We're not getting it anymore. Over.
求救者 请求通话 你在什么位置?
Distressed caller, make another transmission. What is your position?
格雷?
Greg?
到甲板下面去 穿上救生衣
Get below deck now. Get the life jackets.
割断它 把绳子割断
Out it. Out the sail.
维多 把主帆降下来
Vic, get the main sail down.
降下来
Get it down.
维多!
Vic!
没事!
No!
回来
Get back.
洁西 抓住我的手
Jess, take my hand.
抓紧了
Grab on.
希德!
Heather!
抓紧
Grab on.
希德!
Heather!
维多!
Vic!
洁西
Jess.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
还好
All right.
唐尼?
Downey?
大家怎么样?
Are you guys okay?
看见希德了吗? 她刚才被海浪从窗口卷走了
Have you seen Heather? She got lost through the window.
没有 快上来 上来
No. Come on, come on.
希德!
Heather!
格雷! 救我!
Greg! Help me!
莎莉 莎莉
Sally. Sally.
把手给我
Just give me your hand.
希德!
Heather!
大家还好吗?
Are you guys okay?
还好
Yeah.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
汤米在上学 是吗?
Tommy's at school, yeah?
我们回去之后会好好照顾他的 他会很好的
He'll be looked after until we get back. He'll be all right.
谢天谢地 唷! 救救我们!
Thank God. Yo! Help us!
救救我们 救救我们 过来这儿
Help us. Help. Help us. Over here.
噢 老天
Oh, God.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
等等 过来这儿 过来!
Wait. Come on, over here!
看那儿 那儿 就在那儿 我看见有人
There, there. Over there. I can see someone.
风  神  号
唷 我们这儿需要帮助
Yo, we need some help down here.
请帮帮我们!
Help us, please!
唷 我们这儿需要帮助
Hello. We need some help down here.
啊 他看见我们了 他看见我们了
Yeah, he's seen us. He's seen us.
风  神  号
噢 感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
跳过来 跳过来 跳过来
Jump, jump, jump.
没事的 洁西 过来 过来
Okay. Jess, come on, come on.
洁西 过来
Jess. Come on.
过来 过来 抓着我的手 好的
Come on, come on, take my hand. Okay.
好了 你还好吗?
Okay. You okay?
A 甲 板
还好吗? 嗯?
You okay? Yeah?
嗯
Hey.
怎么了?
How is it?
看见人了吗? 明明有的
See? I told you.
有人吗?
Hello?
有人吗!
Hello!
我们就这么待着吗?
Do we wait?
不 我们去舰桥
No, let's go to the bridge.
A 甲 板
我们去找船长 想法子给海岸警卫队打个电话
We'll get the captain to put a call out to the coast guard.
我们去找希德
We'll get a search for Heather.
走吧
Oome on.
你觉得希德会不会已经上来了?
Do you think Heather would've made it on board?
宝贝
Honey.
有这种可能 不是吗?
There's a chance, isn't there?
是的 是的 有这种可能
Yeah. Yeah, there's a chance.
保持过道畅通
每时每刻
六号门
长      廊
有人吗?
Hello?
保持过道畅通
每时每刻
六号门
长      廊
有没有人!
Hello!
有没有人来帮帮我们?
Somebody please help us?
有人吗?
Hello?
人都他妈的去哪儿了?
Where the fuck is everybody?
我们这是要去哪儿
You don't even now where we're going.
喔 我们只是 只是...走走看吧
Well, we're just, just walking for the sake of it.
你还好吗?
You all right?
我觉得我来过这地方
I feel like I know this place.
我认得这走廊
I recognize this corridor.
游轮看上去都差不多
Liners, they look pretty similar.
不 不是这样
No, that's not it.
来看看这个
Come check this out.
就是这艘船 这是艘旧船
This is the same ship. This thing's old.
洁西
Jess.
走吧 走吧
Oome on. Oome on.
1932年 就是这艘船 我们就在这艘船上
1932. It's the same. Here's where we boarded.
噢 是的
Oh, yeah.
埃厄洛斯
Aeolus.
埃厄洛斯是希腊风神 也是西绪福斯的父亲
Aeolus was the Greek god of the winds and the father of Sisyphus,
就是那个被神责罚的人 把石头推上山
the man condemned by the gods to the task of pushing a rock up a mountain
再眼睁睁的看着它滚下来
and let it see roll back down again.
真实差劲的惩罚 他干了什么?
That's a shitty punishment. What did he do?
他欺骗了死神 不 他对死神做了承诺却没有遵守
He cheated Death. No, he made a promise to Death that he didn't keep.
我以前知道但现在记不清了 我们能不能不要管这个继续向前走?
I studied it but I can't remember. Can we just keep on moving, please?
谁啊?
Hello?
可能有人回来拿这个
Whoever it was might wanna come back for these.
让我看看?
Let me see?
这是我的
These are mine.
是我的钥匙
These are my keys.
你瞎说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
这是我的
They're mine.
胡扯
Bullshit.
这是 这是我家里的钥匙
This is, this is my house key.
这是我的 我的车钥匙 这是我儿子 看见了吗?
This is my, my car key. This is my son. See?
等等 就是说在我们游艇上的时候你就带着它们?
Wait. So you had them with you on the yacht?
是的
Yes.
肯定是希德
It's gotta be Heather.
得了吧
Come on.
还有谁会拿到这个?
How else did they get here?
希德难道会把钥匙扔在这儿却不出来说一声 "我没淹死"
It was Heather dropping her keys but not bothering to say, "I didn't drown."
为什么不会?
Why not?
走吧
Come on.
希德?
Heather?
看起来是碰上了一场盛宴 却没人出来迎接
Looks like you get your welcome party, just not the welcome.
希德!
Heather!
唷 格雷 你的表几点了?
Yo, Greg, what time you got?
十一点半
Eleven thirty.
希德
Heather.
希德!
Heather!
人都去哪儿了?
Where is everyone?
希德!
Heather!
莎莉! 好了 不要再叫了
Sally! Please. Please.
我不知道人都去哪儿了 但这肯定不是艘被废弃的船
I don't know where everyone is but the ship's not deserted.
我是说 我们当中可能有人认为它是 但它实际上不是
I mean, maybe some of us think that it is but it's not,
所以我们只需要到舰桥上去
so let's just go to the bridge.
找到船长 然后我们就可以回家了
We'll find the skipper and then we'll go home.
有人
I saw someone.
操
Fuck.
等等
Wait.
谁?
Hello?
你看清楚是谁了吗? 是不是希德?
Did you see who it was? Was it Heather?
我没看清
I didn't see.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你去哪儿?
Where're you going?
只是出去一下 不要管我好不好?
Why don't you just help me out here?
什么?
What?
待在这儿等维多
Just wait for Vic.
什么?
What?
没事的
It's fine.
我们为什么不一起去?
Why can't we go with him?
咱们就在这儿等维多 就照格雷说的办 好不好?
Let's just do as Greg says and wait here for Victor, okay?
好吧
Fine.
我觉得维多有危险
I think Victor's in danger.
我并不担心维多
I'm not worried about Victor.
对不起我可能表现的很怪异 可是我每转过一个拐角
I'm sorry I'm acting weird. It's just I'm having deja vu
都会觉得似曾相识
every time I turn a corner.
不不不
No, no. No.
我来过这地方
I know this place.
不 你没来过这地方 你只不过是吓坏了
No, you don't know this place. You're just in shock.
真搞笑
That's funny.
因为什么? 因为什么? 是因为汤米吗?
What is it? What is it? Is it Tommy?
离开他觉得不安? 是那样的吗? 你觉得不安?
Is it guilt? Is that what it is? Do you feel guilty?
有人吗?
Hello?
去 剧 院
有人吗
Hello.
有人吗?
我们在三层 舰桥在正上方两层
We're on the third floor. The bridge is exactly two floors above us.
格雷 那是血 你就这么打算装看不见吗?
Greg, that was blood. Are you just gonna ignore it?
我了解那些在船上工作的家伙
I know guys that work on ships like this.
他们看见我们 觉得无聊 就想出这种鬼点子发泄他们的精力
They see us, they get bored. They're just letting off some steam.
什么? 你说他们把我们从海里救起来然后再躲起来恶作剧吗?
What? They rescue us from the sea and then they just hide for fun?
是的
Yeah.
嗯 你怎么看?
Well, what's your theory?
我不知道 但我不是 绝对不是吓傻了瞎说
I don't know, but I'm not, but I'm not in shock.
我要回宴会厅 我要下船
I'll be in the ball room. I'm getting off this ship.
洁西 操! 难道你不明白那些只是你在胡思乱想吗?
Jess, fuck! Don't you see that this is all just in your mind?
洁西! 船不是在哪儿都会突然冒出来的
Jess! Ships don't just magically appear out of nowhere.
它们有自己的航线 我是说 你脑袋里想的好像它们是乱窜的一样
They have skippers. I mean, in your world right now they don't.
我脑袋里想的是到学校门口去接孩子回家
My world is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up.
别对我的想法说三道四
Don't talk to me about my world.
洁西 洁西 对不起
Jess. Jess, I'm sorry.
风 神
这是血吗?
Is that blood?
宝贝 别这样 我们得去剧场和别人会合
Babe, come on, we're supposed to meet them in the theater.
希德!
Heather!
通往酒店的宴会大厅
噢 天哪 可恶
Oh, my God. Shit.
莎莉 莎 别这样
Sally. Sal, come on.
咱们只需要去剧场等着
Let's just go to the theater.
通  往
剧 院
唐尼 没有血了 我觉得她不在这儿
Downey, I can't see anymore blood. I don't think she's in here.
跟你说实话 我觉得她根本就不在船上
To be honest with you, I don't think she's even on the ship.
是吗 那这些血是怎么回事?
Okay. So whose blood was that?
人呢?
Hello?
唐尼? 莎莉?
Downey? Sally?
维多 出什么事了?
Victor. What happened?
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
撑住 格雷 撑住 老兄
Stay with me, Greg. Stay with me, man.
撑住 老兄
Stay with me, man.
不 不!
No. No!
你个臭婊子! 你对他开枪!
You fucking bitch! You shot him!
什么?
What?
他说的你对他开枪
He said you shot him.
我没有!
I didn't!
无耻的骗子!
Fucking liar!
我根本没和他一起!
I wasn't even with Greg!
他死了! 死了! 看哪!
He's dead! He's dead! Look!
天哪 你个婊子!
God, you're a bitch!
把你的爪子从他身上拿开!
Get your hands off him!
我没杀死他! 我跟维多在一起
I didn't do it! I was with Victor.
有人袭击了他
Someone attacked him.
有人?
Someone?
你以为是我做的?
You think I did it?
为什么要我们来剧场?
Why did you tell us to come to the theater?
我没有 我... 莎莉 我没有
I didn't. L... Sally, I didn't.
我没有
I didn't.
天哪 你他妈的可真能装
My God, you're a fucking skitso.
莎莉 不
Sally, no.
莎莉!
Sally!
不!
No!
唐尼!
Downey!
快走 快走
Let it go. Let it go.
不!
No!
船 员 进 入
船 甲 板
上 甲 板
四号门
上楼梯到救生艇
别开枪 求你了
Don't shoot. Please.
求你了 别开枪 别开枪
Please, don't shoot. Please.
我还有个儿子 我还有个儿子
I have a son. I have a son.
可恶
Shit.
你是谁? 告诉我!
Who are you? Tell me!
你是谁?
Who are you?
你他妈的在说什么?
What the fuck are you saying?
这是回家的唯一方法
It's the only way to get home.
什么?
What?
你必须杀了他们
You have to kill them.
杀了他们! 杀了他们! 杀了他们!
Kill them! Kill them! Kill them!
看那儿 过来 嘿!
Over here. Come on. Hey!
请帮帮我们!
Help us, please!
救我们!
Help!
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
帮帮我们!
Help us!
请帮帮我们!
Please!
那儿 看那儿 就在那边 我看见有人
There, there. Over there. I can see somebody.
风 神 号
请帮帮我们!
Please!
有人吗?
Hello?
或许他们想搞个欢迎仪式
Looks like they decided to scratch the welcome.
我们去舰桥
Let's go to the bridge.
我们去找船长 想法子给海岸警卫队打个电话
We'll get the captain to put a call out to the coast guard.
有人吗!
Hello!
有人吗?
Hello?
人都他妈的去哪儿了?
Where the fuck is everybody?
我们这是要去哪儿?
Do you even know where we're going?
喔 我们只是 只是...走走看吧
Well, we're just, just walking for the sake of it.
你还好吗?
You all right?
我觉得我来过这地方
I feel like I know this place.
我认得这走廊
I recognize this corridor.
游轮看上去都很像
Liners, they look pretty similar.
不 不是这样的
No, that's not it.
洁西 走吧
Jess, come on.
就是这艘船 这是艘老家伙
This is the same ship. This thing's old.
是啊 1932年的
Yeah. 1932.
就是这艘船 我们就在这艘船上
It is the same. Here's where we boarded.
是的 埃厄洛斯
Yeah. Aeolus.
埃厄洛斯
Aeolus.
埃厄洛斯是希腊风神 也是西绪福斯的父亲
Aeotus was the Greek god of the winds and the father of Sisyphus,
就是那个被神责罚的人 把石头推上山
the man condemned by the gods to the task of pushing a rock up a mountain
再眼睁睁的看着它滚下来
only to have it roll back down again.
真实差劲的惩罚 他做错了什么?
That's a shitty punishment. What did he do?
他欺骗了死神 不 他对死神做了承诺却没有遵守
He cheated Death. No, he made a promise to Death that he didn't keep.
我以前知道但现在记不清了 我们能不能不要管这个继续向前走?
I studied him and I can't remember. Can we just keep on moving?
有人吗?
Hello?
希德?
Heather?
有人吗!
Hello!
希德!
Heather!
莎莉 别叫了 我不知道人都去哪儿了
Sally. Please. I don't know where everyone is.
但这肯定不是艘被废弃的船
But the ship's not deserted.
我是说 我们当中可能有人认为它是但它实际上不是
I mean, maybe some of us think that it is but it's not,
所以我们只需要到舰桥上去
so let's]ust go to the bridge.
找到船长 然后我们就可以回家了
We'll find the skipper and then we go home.
有人
I saw someone.
楼梯到船甲板
有人吗?
Hello?
有人吗
Hello.
操 你怎么跑的这么快?
Shit. How did you get here so fast?
维多 你得 你得听我说 我们时间不多了
Victor, you got, you gotta listen to me. We don't have much time.
哦 怎么了? 格雷呢?
Oh, what's going on? Where's Greg?
他死了
He's dead.
什么?
What?
不 我是说 他刚才死了 但现在还没死
No, I mean, he was dead. He's not dead now.
你说什么呢?
What are you saying?
楼下现在有另一个我
Downstairs right now is a copy of myself.
另一个 正跟格雷一起
Me, walking and talking with Greg.
什么啊
Right.
看那儿
There.
一群鸟
There's birds.
不 那是唐尼的尸体
No, that was Downey's body.
我刚从唐尼那儿过来 你怎么跑的这么快?
I just left Downey back there. How did you get here so fast?
我就是想给你说明白这个
That's what I've been trying to tell you.
不 唐尼刚才在这儿 他的尸体刚才在这儿
No. Downey was there. It was Downey's body.
刚刚船上到处都是尸体
There are bodies all over this ship.
你的尸体就在餐厅的地板上 脑袋上有个洞
Your body is on the floor at the restaurant with a hole in your head.
听着 我卖你个人情 好吧 ?
Listen, I'm gonna do you a favor, okay?
这事儿我不会跟其他人说的
I'm not gonna tell anyone about this.
这是真的 维多 我们必须马上下船
It's the truth. Victor, we gotta get off this ship right now.
你说现在有两个你
You're saying there's two of you now.
对
Yes.
而且我死在餐厅了
And I'm dead in the restaurant.
你被人杀了
You were killed.
好 所以 我死了 唐尼泡在水里 他也死了
Okay. So, I'm dead. Downey's in the water. He's dead, too.
莎莉呢?
Is Sally okay?
这样的话我会得出什么结论?
See where I'm going with this, right?
如果我们都死了 而且还有两个你
If we are dead and there's two of you,
那我们还怎么下船?
how are we all gonna get off this ship?
我们根本就不该上来
We should never have boarded this ship.
我知道有些什么不对
I knew something was wrong.
我不该坚持出航的 这样你们就不会出事了
I should've forced you to stay on the yacht and you'd all be alive.
我打算告诉你我觉得我现在活的好好的
I've gotta tell you I feel pretty alive right now.
很快你就会死了 那些真的发生过 以前发生过
Soon you're gonna be dead. Everything that happened to you, happened before.
真不敢相信我会谈论这些乱七八糟的东西
I can't even believe I'm talking this shit.
你会死的 然后是唐尼 莎莉和格雷
You will die and then, then Downey and Sally and then Greg.
那不会是我干的 不是我干的
I didn't do this. I didn't do it.
我们在三层
We're on the third level.
格雷 那是血 你就这么打算装看不见吗?
Greg, that was blood. You just gonna ignore it?
我了解那些在船上工作的家伙
I know guys that work on ships like this.
他们看见我们 觉得无聊 就想出这种鬼点子发泄他们的精力
They see us, they get bored. They're just letting off some steam.
难道你不明白那些只是你在胡思乱想吗?
Don't you see that this is all just in your mind?
船不是在哪儿都会突然冒出来的
Ships don'just magically appear out of nowhere.
它们有自己的航线 我是说 你脑袋里想的好像它们是乱窜的一样
They have skippers. I mean, in your world right now they don't.
我脑袋里想的是到学校门口去接孩子回家
My wortd is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up.
别对我的想法说三道四
Don't talk to me about my world.
你是谁?
Who are you?
如果他们登船
把他们全部杀死
你是谁?
Who are you?
听着 听我说
Listen, listen to me.
拜托 一定要听
Please, you have to listen.
把他们全杀了
Kill them all.
要是他们上船 就把他们全杀了
If they board, kill them.
军械库
禁止入内!
只有经过授权
人员进入
■
洁西洁西 你得杀了他们
Jess. Jess, you gotta kill them.
拜托 一定要听
Please, you have to listen.
别让他们上船
Don't let them board.
不 不 不 不要 不要 别说了 别说了
No, no. No. Please, please. Stop, stop them.
要是他们上船 就杀了他们
If they board, kill them.
洁西 洁西 你得杀了他们
Jess. Jess, you gotta kill them.
要是他们上传 就杀了他们
If they board, kill them.
不 不 不 不要 不要 别说了 要是他们上船 就杀了他们
No, no. No. Please, please, stop. If they board, kill them.
不要 不要说了 洁西 洁西 洁西
Please, please stop. Jess, Jess, Jess.
去你妈的!
Fuck you!
可恶
Shit.
汤米
Tommy.
这是血吗?
Is that blood?
宝贝 别这样 我们得去剧场和别人会合
Babe, come on. We're supposed to meet them at the theater.
风 神
维多
Victor.
我不会伤害你的
I didn't mean to hurt you.
你知道我不会伤害你的 是吗?
You know I didn't mean to hurt you, right?
现在 我要想法子让大家下船 明白吗?
Now, I'm gonna try and get us off this ship, okay?
莎莉
Sally.
莎莉?
Sally?
维多?
Victor?
怎么了?
What happened?
你不是我
You're not me.
看到了吗? 我没疯
You see? I'm not crazy.
维多
Victor.
刚才的事不是这样的 记得吗?
This didn't happen before. Don't you see?
你刚才想掐死我 还记得吗?
You tried to strangle me, remember?
现在 撑着点 我去找其他人
Now, you gotta be strong. I'm gonna get the others.
唐尼 做点什么
Downey, do something.
撑着点 老兄
Stay with me, man.
做点什么
Do something.
我不知道怎么办
I don't know what to do.
他死了吗? 死了吗?
Is he dead? Is he dead?
格雷 格雷
Greg. Greg.
你个臭...
You fucking...
听着 我不想伤害你们 我们时间不多了
Listen, I'm not gonna hurt you. We don't have much time.
别拿那东西指着我们
Don't you point that thing.
闪开!
Move!
快走 快 快
Go, go, go.
我打中她了 我觉得我打中她了
I hit her. I think I hit her.
发生什么了? 那是怎么回事?
What's going on? Who was that?
发生过的事情又来了一遍 就是这么回事
It's starting over again. That's what's going on.
走吧
Let's go.
我们不能把格雷丢下
We can't leave without Greg.
我们会回来找他的 我保证 走吧 快走!
We'll come back for Greg. I promise. Let's go, come on!
我们能改变这事 看到了吗?
We can change the pattern. Don't you see?
我们能改变 我们不会陷在这儿 然后我们就下船
We change the pattern, we're not trapped. Then we get off this thing.
该死的 她一定是疯了
She's fucking mad.
你这么想?
You think?
你们听我说
You have to listen to me.
不 我们不要听你说
No, I don't have to listen to you.
是"我"向你开枪的吗?
Was it me that shot you?
我不知道
I don't know.
喔 等等 我们能不能先喘口气?
Whoa, wait. Could we just take a breath for a second?
好吧 洁西 我准备听你说
Okay, Jess, I am prepared to listen to you
甚至相信你 但是你得做些解释
and even to believe you, but you gotta make some sense.
我会解释清楚的 我去接维多 然后我们就下船
I'm making perfect sense. I'm gonna get Victor, then we get off this ship.
待在这儿
Wait here.
谁也不要相信
And don't trust anyone.
不管谁来了 开枪打他
If anyone comes, you shoot them.
你在说些什么?
What are you talking about?
开枪打他
You shoot them.
什么?
What?
维多
Victor.
维多?
Victor?
谁在那儿?
I said who is it?
我说谁在那儿?
是我 洁西
It's me, Jess.
耶稣基督 你他妈的到底怎么回事?
Jesus Christ, what the fuck happened to you?
说来话长
A long story.
维多呢?
Where's Victor?
他死了
He's dead.
失足掉到海里了
He fell over the side.
我们怎么知道是不是你杀了他?
How do we know you didn't kill him?
你不用知道
You don't.
想活的话 就跟我来
If you wanna live, you'll follow me.
唐尼!
Downey!
别问
Ignore it.
唐尼!
Downey!
怎么回事?
What's going on?
我说了 别问
Is said ignore it.
你们在哪? 回话
Where are you? Call out.
不 我不能不问 到底怎么回事?
No, t'm not]ust gonna ignore it. What is going on?
你们在哪儿?
Where the fuck are you?
回话! 你们有危险 你们有危险
Call out! You're in danger. You're in danger.
那是谁?
Who is that?
谁也不是?
Not who you think?
呃 我们来这儿干什么?
So, what are we doing in here?
莎莉!
Sally!
等等!
Wait!
抱歉 但我爱我儿子
I'm sorry but I love my son.
莎莉?
Sally?
刚才那不是我
That wasn't me.
莎莉?
Sally?
喂? 喂?
Hello? Hello?
拜托 有人听到吗?
Please, can you hear me?
帮帮我 请帮帮我
Help me. Please, help me.
她杀了所有人
She's killing everyone.
他们死了 他们都死了 请...
They're dead. They're all dead. Please...
莎莉?
Sally?
你在什么位置? 完毕
What's your position? Over.
莎莉
Sally.
求救者 我们听到你了 你在什么位置? 完毕
Distressed caller, we hear you. What are your coordinates? Over.
海岸警卫队 是否听到求救电话? 我们跟她失去联系了 完毕
Coast guard, did you hear a distress call? We're not getting in anymore. Over.
格雷
Greg.
格雷 是你吗?
Greg, is that you?
求救者 请求通话 你在什么位置?
Distressed caller, make another transmission. What is your position?
格雷 能听到我吗? 格雷
Greg, can you hear me? Greg.
可恶
Shit.
莎莉?
Sally?
噢 天哪 你怎么了?
Oh, my God, what happened to you?
离我远点
Get away from me.
刚才那不是我 莎莉 我没有伤害你
It wasn't me, Sally. I didn't do this to you.
刚才那不是我 唐尼呢?
It wasn't me. Where is Downey?
我不知道他在哪儿
I don't know where he is.
是你杀了他
You killed him.
什么?
What?
不 我没有 我没杀他
No, I didn't. I didn't kill him.
什么?
What?
我发誓
I swear.
你疯了
You're crazy.
为什么这么做?
Why are you doing this?
莎莉 我知道这很难 但你要相信我
Sally, I know it's hard but you gotta trust me.
相信我 好吗?
Gotta trust me, okay?
听着 坚持住
Listen, you gotta hold on.
我觉得还会再发生一次
I think it will return again.
我们的小艇 三角号 我想它会再来的
The yacht, the Triangle, I think it'll come back.
要是那样的话 我们就逃走 你和我一起
If it does, we'll escape, me and you together.
我们一起上船逃走
We'll re-board it and escape.
求求你
Please.
不要伤害我
Don't hurt me.
莎莉 我不会的
Sally, I'm not gonna hurt you.
只要你坚持住
If you hold on,
肯定会再见到唐尼的
you can see Downey again.
嘿 过来 来这儿
Hey, come on. Over here.
嘿 嘿 帮帮我们
Hey. Hey. Help.
人死光了就会重新开始
It returns when they're dead.
人死光了船就会再来
It returns when everyone's dead.
你觉得希德 会不会在船上?
Do you think Heather woutd've made it on board?
宝贝
Honey.
有这种可能 不是吗?
There's a chance, isn't there?
是的 是的 有这种可能
Yeah. Yeah, there's a chance.
停下 你这东西
Stop this thing.
停下 你这该死的
Stop this fucking thing.
停下
Please.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
他死了 我是说 他刚才死了
He's dead. I mean, he was dead.
但现在还没死
He's not dead now.
我躲起来 看到了另一个自己
I was hiding and I saw this version of myself,
她脸上有血 我杀了她
and she had blood on her face, and then I killed her.
就在船头那儿我杀了她
I killed her on the front of the ship.
听着 我卖你个人情 好吧?
Listen, I'm gonna do you a favor, okay?
这些话我不会告诉别人的
I'm not gonna tell anyone about this.
这是真的 你要相信我
It's the truth. You gotta listen to me.
不 我一个字也不想听你多说了
No, I'm not listening to another word you say.
你会死的 然后是格雷 然后是唐尼
You will die, and then Greg and then Downey.
别怕 维多 我能救你
Don't be scared, Victor. I can save you.
我知道怎么能救你
I know how to save you.
你应该吃点东西 宝贝
You should try and eat, babe.
洁西?
Jess?
老天 你怎么了?
Jesus, what happened to you?
格雷呢?
Where's Greg?
格雷让我告诉你们在剧场会合
Greg told me to tell you we should meet in the theater.
这儿有个剧场?
There's a theater?
对 就在那边
Yes, it'just that way.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
我去那儿等你们
I'll see you there.
好吧 她现在可真把我搞糊涂了
Okay, she's really starting to freak me out now.
难道你不明白那些只是你在胡思乱想吗?
Don't you see that this is all just in your mind?
船不是在哪儿都会突然冒出来的他们有自己的航线
Ships don't]ust magically appear out of nowhere. They have skippers.
你脑袋里想的好像它们是到处乱窜的一样
In your world right now maybe they don't.
我脑袋里想的是到学校门口去接孩子回家
My wortd is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up.
别对我的想法说三道四
Don't talk to me about my world.
洁西
Jess.
洁西 对不起
Jess, I'm sorry.
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
呃
Okay.
别紧张 老兄
Take it easy, man.
别紧张
Just take it easy.
我们做错了什么吗? 我们本来不是这船上的
What did we do? We're not part of this boat.
我们刚上来 明白吗? 我们只是到处走走 船上没人
We just got here, okay? We've been walking around. There's no one on it.
我可以马上就走 我会走的
I can go right now. I will go.
好吗? 别... 别紧张
Okay? Just... Just take it easy.
别紧张
Take it easy.
好吗?
Okay?
洁西?
Jess?
洁西
Jess.
洁西 你在干什么?
Jess, what are you doing?
这...这是什么? 为...你穿的什么东西?
Wha... what is this? Why... what are you wearing?
我不想让你看见我的脸
I don't want you to see my face.
为什么?
Why?
因为这不是我
Because this is not me.
我正在远离这儿某处的小艇上 和你在一起
I'm somewhere out there in the yacht and you're with me.
杀了你之后 我们会重新来过
And after I kill you, we'll return.
那样么?
Is that right?
我说 为-为什么 你不先放下枪?
You know, why-why don't you just put down the gun first?
好吗? 来
Okay? Come on.
知道吗 你们死光了之后小船就会再回来
You see, the boat comes back when you're all dead.
我做的正是以前发生过的事情
I've done everything exactly like before.
但这次小船来的时候 我会准备好 等在那儿
But when the boat comes back, I'll be ready, I'll be waiting.
我会等在登船的地方 阻止他们上来 即便是另一个我
I'll be on the landing bay. I won't let any of them board, even the other me.
我会让他们留在翻了的小艇上
I'll make them all stay on the upturned yacht.
好的
Okay.
洁西 我们会照你说的做
Jess, we'll do whatever you want.
好吗? 只是 只是先放下枪
Okay? Just, just put down the gun.
来
Come on.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不 不 不 不!
No, no, no, no!
格雷!
Greg!
噢 天哪! 发生什么事了?
Oh, God! What happened?
是洁西干的
It was Jess.
你个臭婊子! 你对他开枪 他说你对他开枪
You fucking bitch! You shot him. He said you shot him.
我根本没和他一起!
I wasn't even with Greg!
他死了! 他死了!
He's dead! He's dead!
天哪 你他妈的可真能装
My God, you're a fucking skitso.
唐尼!
Downey!
求求你
Please.
不要杀我
Don't kill me.
我还有个儿子
I have a son.
你是谁?
Who are you?
告诉我!
Tell me!
他们会回来的
They'll return.
你是谁?
Who are you?
他们会回来的 你必须要杀死他们
They'll return. You have to kill them.
这是回家的唯一方法
It's the only way to get home.
你他妈的在说什么?
What the fuck are you saying?
这是救我们儿子的唯一方法
It's the only way to save our son.
你必须杀死他们
You have to kill them.
杀死他们? 杀死他们?
Kill them? Kill them?
快点 宝贝 我们要迟到了
Hurry up, Sweetheart. We're gonna be tate.
我给你买东西就是为了
What's fun in buying you things
让你把它们扔在那该死的院子里吗!
if you're gonna leave them in the fucking garden!
说这些我都说的烦透了 汤米
I'm sick of telling you this, Tommy.
我不会再给你买玩具了 除非你能把手头上这些都整理好
I ain't buying you anymore toys if you can't look after the ones you've got.
又怎么了?
Now what?
呃 我刚打扫干净的 我是不是该...?
Oh, I'll just clean it up, shall I?
我刚清理干净这一团糟!
Yeah, I'm]ust cleaning the fucking mess!
你到底怎么回事 啊? 你到底是怎么回事?
What's the matter with you, huh? What's the matter with you?
你就不能让我安心一天吗 就他妈的一天!
Just one day off is alt I ask. Just one fucking day off!
真不知道你怎么就不能跟个正常孩子一样画画
I don't know why you can't paint a picture like a normal kid.
肯定是从你老爸那儿遗传的
You get this from your father.
他也是个混蛋
He was an asshole, too.
可恶
Shit.
杰克?
Jack?
看到有人按我的门铃吗?
Did you see anyone ring my doorbell?
汤米?
Tommy?
宝贝 来这儿
Sweetheart, come here.
来这儿 来这儿! 没事了
Come here. Come here! It's okay.
妈妈好好的 看到了吗?
Mommy's fine, you see?
妈妈好好的
Mommy's fine.
你刚才只是做了个恶梦 只是个恶梦 宝贝
You're just having a bad dream. That's all, baby.
只是个恶梦 都过去了
It's all it was.
恶梦让你觉得你看到了实际上不存在的东西
Bad dreams make you think you've seen things that you haven't.
“阳光之州”佛罗里达州
再见
欢 迎
再 来
以后会不同的 汤米
Things are gonna be different now, Tommy.
妈妈再也不会发脾气了
Mommy won't lose her temper anymore,
就算你做错了事情也不会
even when you do things wrong.
而且她再也不会打你了
And she won't hurt you.
我知道她再也不会了
I know she won't hurt you.
知道我为什么知道吗 汤米?
You know how I know that, Tommy?
因为那个做这些事情的女人不是你妈妈
Because that woman that did those things to you is not Mommy.
我才是你妈妈 妈妈可好了
This is Mommy. Mommy's nice.
可恶
Shit.
汤米 待在车里
Tommy, stay in the car.
我去扔了它 好吗?
I'm gonna bury it, okay?
我们得走了 得离开这儿
We have to go. We have to get out of here.
别叫了 宝贝
Stop screaming, babe.
别叫了 汤米 只是血
Please, Tommy, it is just blood.
别叫了!
Stop screaming!
汤米 看 看见了吗? 看那儿 没了
Tommy, look. See? There, it's gone.
看见了吗? 看那儿 没了
See? There. It's gone.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
你是谁?
Who are you?
只是个司机
Just a driver.
那孩子没救了
No point trying to save the boy.
没人能阻止死神把他带走
There's nothing anyone can do that's gonna bring him back.
要我带你一程吗?
Can I give you a ride?
好
Yes.
带我去码头
Take me to the harbor.
嘿
Hey.
我先不关计价器
I'll leave the meter running.
你会回来的 对吗?
You will come back, won't you?
是的 我-我 会的
Yes, I-I promise.
出入境限制
洁西
Jess.
你认识我吗?
Do you know me?
我想是的 格雷跟我谈了很多关于你的事
I feel like I do. Greg talks about you enough.
格雷呢?
Where is Greg?
你觉得呢?
Where do you think?
快一点 你迟到了
Come on, you're late.
你就是那个带孩子的 对吗?
You're the one with the kid, right?
对
Yeah.
怎么没把小孩带来?
How come you didn't bring him along?
他在学校
He's at school.
你确定?
You sure about that?
是的
Yes.
■
安   全
您  正  被
摄  像  头
拍 摄 记 录
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
嘿 怎么了? 出什么事了?
Hey, what's the matter? What happened?
嘿
Hey.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你道什么歉啊 怎么了?
You have nothing to apologize for. What's the matter?
我只是有点累
I'm just tired.
喔 听着 如果你不想的话 我们不一定非得今天出航
Listen, we don't have to go today if you don't want to.
不 我们走 我-我想
No, I do. I-I wanna go.
真的吗?
Are you sure?
是的
Yeah.
是的? 来吧 来这儿
Yeah? Come, come here.
这是莎莉和她丈夫 唐尼
This is Sally and her husband, Downey.
这是希德 莎莉的朋友 你应该还记得维多
This is Heather, Sally's friend. You remember Victor.
现在让我们起航吧!
Let's go sailing.
好
Okay.
剧 终  谢谢观赏